Guide to the Stanford University, International Development Education Center, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, International Development Education Center, records
1966-1990
SC0777
Stanford International Development Education Center
30 Linear feet
Records pertain to administrative matters and to classes offered in the program; included are correspondence, grant files, articles, reports, proposals, and conference materials, 1966-1990.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Stanford International Development Education Center (SIDEC) was founded in 1965 with funding from the US Department of Education and the Ford Foundation. SIDEC prepared foreign nationals to return to their countries and establish effective educational systems.
Description of the Collection
Records pertain to administrative matters and to classes offered in the program; included are correspondence, grant files, articles, reports, proposals, and conference materials, 1966-1990.
Access Terms
Stanford International Development Education Center; Stanford University. Graduate School of Education.; International education.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-2005-328
  - Weiler Chron file 1989-90 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Weiler Chron file 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Weiler Chron file 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Weiler Chron file 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Weiler Chron file 1985 (January) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Weiler Chron file 1984 (2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Weiler Chron file 1984 (1) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Weiler Chron file 1983-84 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Weiler Corresp. May – Aug. 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Weler Corresp. Sept. 1982 – Apr. 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - SIDEC Winter Quarter 1986-87 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - SIDEC Correspondence 1985-86 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Carnoy Chron file 1983-84 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - SIDEC Chron file 1983-84 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - SIDEC Correspondence 1982-83 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - SIDEC Chron file 1981-82 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Carnoy Correspondence file 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Carnoy Correspondence 1982-83 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Carnoy Chron file Jan.-June 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Weiler, Hans, Chron file 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Weiler, Hans N., Chron file July-Dec. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Chron file Apr.-June 1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chron file Jan.-Mar. 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chron file Aug.-Dec. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chron file Apr.-Aug. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chron file Jan.-Mar. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chron file Jul.-Dec. 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chron file Jan.-June 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chron file 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Grossman, David, CHRONological files Oct. 1977-Dec. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fuenzalida, Edmundo, CHRONological files May 1978-Dec. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Textor, Robert B., Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - MICEFA – Stanford SIDEC Seminar Nov. 10-Dec. 1, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - International Development Research Centre Award, Ottawa, 1-CDZ-638 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - IIE – Weiler, Expenditure Statements – Closed, 1-CDZ-626 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - IIE – Weiler, Correspondence, 1-CDZ-626 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Financial Aid – Grubb Scholarship (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Ford Foundation Suballocation, 1-CDF606 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Long Range Planning, ICAA 610 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ford Foundation Fellowship, Expenditure Statements, 1-CAH611 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - IDRC Paper, Closed, 1-CAA-621 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Weiler Faculty Rebate Account, Open, 2-CDA-177 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - NIE Finance and Governance, 2-CDK-458 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Ford Found. Interim Report 3/1/78-2/28/79, 785-0359; 1CAB660 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Ford Francophone W. African Grant, Expenditure Statements, 1-CAB660 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Narrative Report 9/19/79, FWA 785-0359; 1 CAB 660 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - SIDEC, Closed, 1-CAB655 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - SIDEC Correspondence 1-CAB655 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ford Francophone W. African, Open, 785-0359, 1 CAB 660 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Ford Francophone W. African, Closed, 785-0359, 1CAB660 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Ford Foundation Grant, Award Letters and Budgets, 1-CAB660 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Ford Foundation Final Report, 1-CAB660 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Ford Found. Interim Report 3/1/79-2/28/80, 785-0359, 1-CAB660 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Ford Foundation W. African Grant, Closed, 1-CAB-661 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ford Foundation Grant, Award Letters and Budgets, 1-CAB661 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ford Foundation W. African Grant, Open, 1-CAB-661 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ford/S.E. Asia Preliminary Proposal for M.A. Dev. Ed. For Students from S.E. Asia, 7/10/69 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ford Proposal/Drafts (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Research C.R.I.S. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Ford Renewal Proposal, April 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Carnoy and Weiler research proposal, "Education, Planning and the State: Theoretical Reflections on the Political Economy of Planning Educational Reform", Feb. 1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Mary Jacks Thomas Development Education Fund, 1 CAB 640, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Carry-over funds from SEA 700-0218A ($8,053.10) from Sept. 1975- June 30, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Modification of grant 750-0517 – unreported balance of $9,235.36 (supplement) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Ford LA/SEA Award letter 750-0517 9/21/75. $250,000.00 9/1/75 -8/31/77 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - SEA Renewal letter 3/30/72 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Ford/SEA Grant Award, Nov. 1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Ford/S.E. Asia Grant 700-0218, Budget 1-CAB-646 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Actual Expenses Ford, 750-0517 along with carry-over funds from 700-0218, 12/28/78 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - SEA Actual Expense – extension of Grant 700-0218A, closed 6/30/76 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Actual Expenses, Ford Grant 750-0517 1CAB 648; 4CAB648, 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Actual Expenses, Ford 750-0517, $250,000. award, final year reporting 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Actual Expenses, Summary of 3 yr. expenditures 1974-75. Ford 700-0218A (SEA), 1CAB 646, 4CAB647 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Actual Expenses, 1973-74. Ford/SEA 700-0218, 1CAB646, 4CAB647 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Actual Expenses SEA, 1972-73 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Summary of 3-yr. spending. SEA/MA, 1 76 FO83 – 1CAB646; 4CAB647 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Actual Expenses SEA, 1971-72 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Actual Expenses SEA, 1970-71 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - SEA Annual Report 1976-77 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - SEA Annual Report 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - SEA Annual Report/Extension June 1976 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - SEA Annual Report 1974-75 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - SEA Annual narrative report (3/3/75) 1973-74 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - SEA Annual Report (5/21/74) 1972-73 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Ford Narrative Report 1972-73 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - SEA Annual Report (5/21/73) 1971-72 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - SEA Annual Report (11/12/71) 1970-71 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Budget Statements 1976-77, Ford Foundation 700-0517, 1CAB648, 4CAB648 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - LA/Ford Fellows 1976-77 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - SEA OPEN 1976-77 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - SEA/Ford Fellows 1976-77 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Monthly Sheets 1976-77 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Monthly Sheets 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - SEA Fellows 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - SEA T.A.'s 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - SEA Fellows 1974-75 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - SEA T.A.'s 1974-75 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Ford/SEA Budget Statement 4CAB647, 9/1/74-8/31/75 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - SEA Closed 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Ford/SEA Budget Statement 1CAB646, 9/1/74-8/31/75 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - SEA Monthly Sheets 19794-75 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - SEA Closed 1974-75 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - SEA Closed 1973-74 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Ford/SEA Budget Statements 1CAB646, 9/1/73-8/31/74 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Ford/SEA Budget Statements 4CAB647, 9/1/73-8/31/74 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - SEA Open 1973-74 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Ford/SEA Budget Statements 1-CAB-646, 9/1/72-8/31/73 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Ford/SEA Budget Statements-647 Fellows, 9/1/71-8/31/72 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Ford/SEA Budget Statements-646, 9/1/71-8/31/72 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Ford/S.E. Asia- Budget Statements 1-CAB-646, To 8/31/71 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Ford/S.E. Asia-Budget Statements 4-CAB-647, To 8/31/71 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Ford Foundation Grant 765-0481;1CAB654 Carnoy, Martin-Coast Rica Conference (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Ford-4/7/69 Proposal w/ Budget and Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Ford/4A-Contract Budget, 8/26/69 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Grant Award- Ford 690-0638, 1CAB-644 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Ford-LA Renewal #69-638, 9/1/74-8/31/75 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Ford-Stanford M.A. Grant 1-CAB-644, No. 690-0638, 7/1/69-6/30/72 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Ford L.A. Renewal #690-0638A, 7/1/71-8/10/71 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Ford/LA Annual Report 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Ford/LA Annual Report 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Ford/LA Annual Report 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Ford Report/October 31, 1974/LA 690-0638 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Ford/LA Annual Report 1971-72 1/23/73 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Ford Report Oct. 26, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Ford/LA Annual Report 1970-71, 11/5/71 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Ford/LA Annual Report 1969-70, 10/30/70 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Ford Fellowship Programs-Reports: Latin America (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Profile Report to CRIS (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Actual Expense 1975-76, Ford Foundation 750-0157, 1CAB648; 4CAB648 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Actual Expenses 1974-75, Ford Foundation 690-0638 LA (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Actual Expenses 1973-74, Ford Foundation 690-0638 LA (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Ford/LA-Actual Expense Table, 6/9/70-70/71-71/72 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - LA R.A's & Suse Grants 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - LA Fellows 1975-76 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - FORD/LA Budget Statements 1 CAB644, 9/1/74-8/31/1975 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Ford/LA Budget Statements 4CAB645, 9/1/74-8/31/75 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - LA Fellows 74-75 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Ford/LA Budget Statements, 1-CAB-644, 9/1/73-8/31/74 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Ford/LA Budget Statements, 4-CAB-645, 9/1/73-8/31/74 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Ford/LA Budget Statements, 4-645, 9/1/72-8/31/73 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Ford/LA Budget Statements 644, 9/1/72-8/31/73 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Ford/L.A. Budget Statements 1-CAB-644, 9/1/71-8/31/72 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ford/L.A.-Budget Statements 645=9/1/71-8/31/72 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - L.A. Becarios 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 8/29-9/29/71- L.A. Conference Kenigston, Jamacia SHEET (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Consulation 1972-73 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - MCT-Jamicia Conf. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Weiler Memos-Assistantships Funds- 6/11/1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ford/L.A. Budget Statements 1-CAB-644, 9/1/70-8/31/71 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1970 Becario Conference Cartagena, Colombia, Sept 14-19 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - SIDEC Fundraising (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - SIDEC IDE and Operating Procedures (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Orientation Fall 73 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Retreat Oct. 20, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - SIDEC Pending (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - SUSE Evaluation Group (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Teaching (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - SIDEC Brochure (rev.) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - University- Bay Area China Education Project(BAYCEP)David Grossman (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Pol. Sci-IDE Search-General (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Abramson, Paul (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Lewis Brownstein (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Dawson, Richard (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - SIDEC-Philosophy (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - SIDEC-Indonesia Project (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - SIDEC- IDE & Policy(SIDEC/C&IDE) (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - SIDEC-IDE & Memos to Students (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - SIDEC-IDE Obsolescence Paper (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - SIDEC-IDE & Memos to IDE Committee (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - SIDEC-Ford Foundation and ETV (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - SIDEC-IDE-Financial Aid 1974-75 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - SIDEC-IDE & Courses 1973-74 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - SIDEC-IDE & A.I.D. (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - SIDEC-Faculty & Inkeles (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Suzman, Richard (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Murray, Bernie (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Herring, Ron (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Greenberg, Ed (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Hanna, William John (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Hennessey, Timothy (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Inglehart, Ronald (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Langton, Kenneth P. (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Niemi, Richard (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Scott, Robert (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Wurfel, David (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - SIDEC-2 Brochures (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Carnoy, Martin 73 Conference; Comments on Economic Development and Income Distribution in Lat. America (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - L.A. M.A. Program in I.D.E. Summer Conference in Cartagena, Columbia 1970 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Reflexiones sobre la Education no Formal en el Medio Rural Latino-Americano (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - 1973 SIDEC Conference in Costa Rica (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Conferencia Sobre Refoma Educativa Mexico-1972 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Martin Convoy. EUROPE-General Trip Information (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - LONDON: Matin Carnoy (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Mexico Conference (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Mexico Seminar (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Jamaica Conference (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Lima Institute (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - List of Participants and Participant Address List (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Seminario Internacional Sobre Education No Formal en el Medio Rural: Investigacion y Desarrollo (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Seminario del Programa de Estudios Conjuntos Sobre Integracion Economica Latinoamericana (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Two papers: "A Study of the Drop Out Phenomena I the College of Arts, Science and Technology**Jamaica" and "Esquema de la Presentacion de el Salvador" August 1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Peru-Special Meetings of the Commission Dec. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Seminario Segundo sobre Investigacion y Planificacion de los Costros de la Educacion (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Seminario Internacional Sobre "Educacion no Formal en el Medio Rural: Investigacion y Desarrollo (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Pacific Research and World Empire Telegram, Nov. 1970 (Pacific Studies Center publication) with article on secondary education by Rick Greenspan (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - International Development Education Conference – Kingston Jamaica, summary of conference, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Conference-Quito, Ecuador, July 1967 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Conference, Mexico, Dec. 1966 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - LACDES Newsletter [Latin American and Caribbean Development Education Students], Vol. II-Vol. VI, 1972-77 (Box 5)
  - Papers from Ed. 306C (1970) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Bock, Prob. Dev. Ed. In SEA, Win. 1971-72 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Bock, Prob. Dev. Ed. In SEA, Sum. 1971-71 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Bock, Prob. Dev. Ed. In SEA, Aut. 1971-72 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Courses, Memos, 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Bock, Prob. Dev. Ed. In SEA, Aut. 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Ed. 207, Prof. Carnoy, Problems of Dev. Ed. in L.A., Aut. 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Ed. 306A, Prof. Carnoy, Education and Economic Development, Aut. 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Bock, Problems of Dev. Ed. In SEA, Win. 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Ed. 207, Prof. Carnoy, Problems of Dev. Ed. in L.A., Win. 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Ed. 209, Prof. Weiler, Problems of Dev. Ed. in Africa, Win. 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Ed. 253, Prof. Holsinger, Computer Applications in Educational Research, Win. 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Ed. 306B, Prof. Weiler, Educ. And Political Devel., Win. 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Ed. 313A, Profs. Carnoy/Weiler, Economics of Education, Win. 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Ed. 406H, Prof. Textor, Res. Colloq. in I.D.E., Win. 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Ed. 406, Prof. Weiler, Research Methodology: practicum, Aut. 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Ed. 452 (Anth 286), Prof. Textor, Anth. Res. Methods w/Implic. for Ed., Win. 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Bock, Spring 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Ed. 306C/Anth. 228, Prof. Textor, Spring 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Ed. 307, Prof. Bock, Spring 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Ed. 406H, Prof. Textor, Spring 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Ed. 408/Pol. Sci. 323, Prof. Weiler, Spring 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Ed. 106, Prof. Carnoy, Summer 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Bock, Summer 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Ed. 207, Prof. Carnoy, Summer 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Ed. 212, Prof. Weiler, Summer 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - SIDEC Workshop, Summer 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Ed. 207, Some Computations for an Educational Plan – An Exercise, Aut. 1972 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Ed. 306 (and other courses), 1969-72 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Courses, I.D.E., memos, 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Ed. 108/P.S. 127B, Prof. Weiler, Aut. 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Bock, Prob. Dev. Ed. In SEA, Aut. 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Ed. 207, Prof. Carnoy, Problems of Dev. Ed. in L.A., Aut. 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Ed. 203B, Prof. Textor, Intro. To IDE, Winter 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Bock, Prob. Dev. Ed. In SEA, Winter 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Ed. 207, Prof. Carnoy, Problems of Dev. Ed. in L.A., Winter 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Ed. 306A, Prof. Carnoy, Education and Economic Development, Aut. 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Ed. 209, Prof. Weiler, Problems of Dev. Ed. in Africa, Winter 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Ed. 254/Anth 286,186, Prof. Textor, Anth. Res. Methods, Winter 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Ed. 307, Prof. Bock, Non-Formal Education, Winter 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Ed. 307, Prof. Bock, supplementary materials, Spring 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Ed. 106, Prof. Carnoy, Spring 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Ed. 203C, Prof. Textor, Res. Colloq. In IDE, Spring 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Bock, Prob. Dev. Ed. In SEA, Spring 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Ed. 306B/P.S. 222, Prof. Weiler, Educ. And Political Devel., Winter 1972-73 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Ed. 306C/Anth. 228, Prof. Textor, Ed. and Sociocultural Change, Spring 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - ED. 408/P.S. 323, Prof. Weiler, Red. Sem on Comp. Study Pol. Sci., Spring 1973-74 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - SIDEC Bag Lunch Colloquium, Spring 1973-74 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Bock, summer 1973-74 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Ed. 306B, Prof. Quick, Winter 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ed. 306C/Anth 228, Prof. Textor, Spring 1973-75 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Ed. 229B, Prof. Textor, Colloquium in IDE, Winter 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Ed. 207, Prof. Carnoy, Dev. Problems in Latin America, Winter 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Paige, Problems of Dev. In SEA, Winter 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Ed. 306A, Prof. Carnoy, Education and Economic Development, Aut. 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Ed. 207, Prof. Carnoy, Dev. Probs. In Latin America, Aut. 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Paige, Problems of Dev. In SEA, Aut. 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Ed. 229A, Prof. Bock, Intro. To Dev. Ed., Aut. 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Ed. 229C, Prof. Textor, Spring 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Ed. 106, Prof. Carnoy, Education as Cultural Imperialism, Spring 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Ed. 206, Prof. Paige, Problems of Dev. In SEA, Spring 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Ed. 207, Prof. Carnoy, Dev. Probs. In Latin America, Spring 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Ed. 313B, Profs. Carnoy and Levin, the Economics of Education, Spring 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Ed. 313A, Profs. Carnoy and Levin, the Economics of Education, Winter 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Ed. 207A, Prof. Carnoy, Problems of Dev. Ed. in Latin America, Aut. 1975-76 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Ed. 306C, Prof. Textor, Spring 1975-76 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Ed. 307, Prof. Bock, Non-Formal Education, Winter 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Courses, IDE, memos, 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Readings (photocopied articles, book chapters) (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Reading, Ed. 106, Carnoy (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Student papers (2) (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Addresses (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Addresses – students and graduates (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Addresses (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Addresses and memos re. (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Addresses: Latin America (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Addresses: Africa (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Addresses: Western Europe (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Addresses: North America (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Addresses: South America (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Addresses: Central America (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Addresses: Eastern Europe (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Addresses: Australia/Oceania (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Addresses: Middle East (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Addresses: Asia (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Appendix A: Characteristics, Occupational Origins and Current Distribution of SIDEC Southeast Asian M.A. Graduates 1970-91 to 1976-77 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Robert Arnove, letter to, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Addresses Asia Foundation (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Alumni Contacts 1986 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - California International Studies Project (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Certificates – M.A. program (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Dr. Rodolfo Cerdas: correspondence re immigration difficulties, 1985-86 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - 1-CAA-102 Research Incentive (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Spanish Grant (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Govt. of the Philippines, 1-CDZ-910 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - 2-CHA-651 Hewlett Foundation – OPEN FILE (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - 2-CHA-651 Hewlett Foundation Carnoy (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - 2-CKA-763 CPRE (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - IIE- Weiler Proposal 1-CDZ-626 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Humphrey Program (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - IIEP Visit (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Evaluation, Ford Foundation MA Training Program in SIDEC, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Latin American and Caribbean Program – form letter on biblio. ref. material (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Ford/Latin America Program – Publishers (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Description of Latin American Fellowship Program (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Ford – personnel prospects (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Frank J. Moore correspondence, Mexico and Jamaica, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Ford Fellowship Program, correspondence and other items, 1969-71 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Ford/Stanford Pre-final Draft Proposal, Feb. 14, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Ford/Stanford – section drafts (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Ford/Stanford proposal draft, Jan. 1969 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Tentative budget – Ford proposal (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Preliminary draft for discussion of a proposal to the Ford Foundation, Dec. 1968 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Frank J. Moore memo on Ford Fellowship Program, Latin America Trip, June 1969 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Ford/Stanford proposal correspondence, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Heberto Urdaneta, Venezuela [did not come], 1970-71 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Visiting Scholars [did not come] 1972 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Schmick, William A. "the Influence of Organizational Positions on Change Implementation in High Schools with Elected and Appointed Department Heads", May 1970 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Schneider, Leslie (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Seymour, James (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Shannon, James V. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Sims, Dennis (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sims, Dennis (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Sims, Dennis (with Peters) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Stern (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Stern, Barry (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Sterns, Maurice A. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Stromquist, Nelly (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Unger, Marvin H. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Wilson, Thomasyne (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - T. Lightfoote Wilson (Tomme), "Liberia" (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Wilson, Thomasyne (Box 7, Folder 15)